<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">MSU Philosophy and Religion</string>
    <string name="app_version">Version 1</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="action_philosphy_home">Philosophy and Religion Home</string>
    <string name="title_activity_news__events">News and Events</string>
    <string name="title_activity_faculty">Faculty</string>
    <string name="title_activity_major">Major</string>
    <string name="religion_major">RELIGION MAJOR</string>
    <string name="title_activity_minor">Minor</string>
    <string name="religion_minor">RELIGION MINOR</string>
    <string name="title_activity_graduates">Graduates</string>
    <string name="title_activity_benfield__prize">Benfield Prize</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_courses">Courses</string>
    <string name="title_activity_msu__home">MSU Home</string>
    <string name="prize_information">David Benfield Philosophy Essay Prize</string>
    <string name="award_date">Spring 2015 Awards</string>
    <string name="first_second">First place $200.00*\nSecond place $100.00*</string>
    <string name="prize_funded">These awards are made possible through a generous grant from the
        Fortune Title Agency of Roseland, NJ.</string>
    <string name="submission_deadline">Submission Deadline: March 13, 2015</string>
    <string name="essay">Essays will be judged by a panel of MSU Philosophy faculty members.
        Winning essays will be selected on the basis of philosophical content, rigor of
        argumentation, style and composition.</string>
    <string name="requirement">Requirements</string>
    <string name="required_info">• Essays on any topic in philosophy may be submitted.\n
        • The author of the essay must be enrolled as a Philosophy Major or Minor at Montclair
        State University.\n
        • The essay may be a revised course essay or a newly composed essay.\n
        • A student may submit only one essay for consideration per year.\n
        • Essays submitted previously may not be submitted a second time.</string>
    <string name="instructions">Instructions</string>
    <string name="instruction_info">• Essays should be formatted properly: standard font, standard
        margins, double-spaced, etc.\n
        • The length of your submission should be between 2,000 and 3,500 words (approximately
        6\u002D12 pages).\n
        • Essays must include a proper bibliography.\n
        • Email your essay as an attachment to Tiger Roholt:</string>
    <string name="prize_contact">roholtt@mail.montclair.edu</string>
    <string name="instruction_info1"> (submit only one of the following file types: \u0022pdf\u0022
        \u0022doc\u0022 \u0022docx\u0022 \u0022pages\u0022)\n
        • Essays should be prepared for blind review (The author\u0027s name should not appear
        anywhere in the essay). The author\u0027s name should appear in the body of the email.</string>
    <string name="winner_info">\u002AFunds will be credited to the winner’s account at Montclair
        State University.</string>
    
    <string name="courses">Fall 2015 Courses</string>
    <string name="class1">PHIL 270 Philosophy of Mind</string>
    <string name="class1_info">Staff\nT 5:30-8:00pm\nWe will explore the following first order
        questions: Is your mind really just your brain?  Is having a mind the same as having
        a soul? Could humans survive bodily death by uploading their minds to a computer? Could
        a computer ever have qualitative experiences? What makes the mental causally efficacious
        rather than causally inert and epiphenomenal?</string>
    <string name="class2">PHIL 310 Knowledge, Belief \u0026 Truth</string>
    <string name="class2_info">Dr. McDermid\nTR 11:30am\u002D12:45pm\nThis course will survey
        questions about the nature and possibility of knowledge (the study of epistemology).
        It\u0027s easiest to explain what the course is about, by saying it’s about a collection
        of questions like these: What is knowledge? Where do we get knowledge? How do we know we
        know something? What is truth? These are, obviously, pretty abstract questions\u002Dthe
        sort philosophy is famous for. And yet, they do have some practical consequences, depending
        upon how you answer them. We will be investigating both the abstract and the more-concrete
        implications of a wide variety of epistemological positions, from skepticism to naive
        realism, and their intersections with other philosophical issues in metaphysics, ethics,
        political and social philosophy.</string>
    <string name="class3">PHIL 331 History of Philosophy: Ancient</string>
    <string name="class3_info">Dr. Herrera\nW 5:30-8:00pm\nAn introduction to the major figures
        of classical philosophy in the ancient world. The course will focus on the writings of
        Plato and Aristotle, the two greatest and most influential thinkers in ancient philosophy.
        The course will also cover the beginnings of philosophy in the Pre-Socratics. The course
        will examine issues including truth, beauty, and goodness; democracy and freedom;
        knowledge, reason, and experience; and reality, time, space, infinity, and God.</string>
    <string name="class4">PHIL 339 Contemporary Continental Philosophy</string>
    <string name="class4_info">Dr. Roholt\nT 1:00-3:30pm\nThis course surveys the four main
        movements of the continental (European) philosophical tradition: (1) 19th century German
        philosophy, (2) Marxism/critical theory, (3) phenomenology/existentialism, and (4)
        post\u002Dstructuralism/post\u002Dmodernism. This philosophical tradition runs from
        the late 19th Century to the present day. Continental philosophy stands in contrast to
        the dominant, Anglo\u002DAmerican, \u0022analytic\u0022 philosophical tradition. This
        course gives students the opportunity to examine the ways in which continental philosophers
        approach issues in the core subfields of philosophy, such as epistemology, metaphysics,
        ethics, political philosophy, and aesthetics. Students will also have the opportunity to
        explore similarities to and differences from the analytic philosophical tradition. We
        will focus on philosophers such as Hegel, Nietzsche, Marx, Adorno, Heidegger, Merleau\u002D
        Ponty, and Foucault.</string>
    <string name="class5">PHIL 424 Seminar: Women Philosophers</string>
    <string name="class5_info">Dr. Rogers\nR 1:00-3:30pm\nPerhaps the best\u002Dkept secret in
        philosophy is the number of women who were engaged in philosophical discussions alongside
        familiar and influential men in the history of the discipline. In this course, we will read
        works of three major women philosophers: Christine di Pizan\u0027s The Body Politic
        (15th century); Mary Wollstonecraft\u0027s The Vindications (18th century);
        and Simone de Beauvoir\u0027s Ethics of Ambiguity (20th century). The aim of the course
        is threefold: To analyze these works in and of themselves, to understand them in the
        context of the larger philosophical tradition, and to evaluate them in relation to each
        other as part of the \u0022genealogy of women\u0027s thought.\u0022 Please note that
        women philosophers were not necessarily feminists. In this course for instance, only some
        of Wollstonecraft\u0027s work is intentionally feminist. Students interested in studying
        other women philosophers (feminist or not) will have the opportunity to do so, but interest
        in feminism is not necessary to benefit from this course.</string>
    
    <string-array name="professor_names">
        <item>David Benfield</item>
        <item>Roland Garrett</item>
        <item>Christopher Herrera</item>
        <item>Kirk McDermid</item>
        <item>Dorothy Rogers</item>
        <item>Tiger Roholt</item>
        <item>Mark Clatterbuck</item>
        <item>Cynthia Eller</item>
        <item>Yasir Ibrahim</item>
        <item>Stephen Johnson</item>
        <item>Michael Kogan</item>
        <item>Lise Vail</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="locations">
        <item>448 Dickson Hall</item>
        <item>452 Dickson Hall</item>
        <item>451 Dickson Hall</item>
        <item>444 Dickson Hall</item>
        <item>455 Dickson Hall</item>
        <item>411 Dickson Hall</item>
        <item>443 Dickson Hall</item>
        <item>450 Dickson Hall</item>
        <item>449 Dickson Hall</item>
        <item>453 Dickson Hall</item>
        <item>445 Dickson Hall</item>
        <item>447 Dickson Hall</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="description">
        <item>Professor of Philosophy</item>
        <item>Professor of Philosophy</item>
        <item>Associate Professor of Philosophy</item>
        <item>Assistant Professor of Philosophy</item>
        <item>Associate Professor of Philosophy</item>
        <item>Associate Professor of Philosophy</item>
        <item>Assistant Professor of Religion</item>
        <item>Professor of Religion</item>
        <item>Associate Professor of Religion</item>
        <item>Professor of Religion</item>
        <item>Professor of Religion</item>
        <item>tenured Assistant Professor of Religion</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_faculty__informartion">Faculty Informartion</string>
    <string-array name="phone">
        <item>(973) 655-4438</item>
        <item>(973) 655-5133</item>
        <item>(973) 655-4435</item>
        <item>(973) 655-6975</item>
        <item>(973) 655-7933</item>
        <item>(973) 655-7556</item>
        <item>(973) 655-7414</item>
        <item>(973) 655-7416</item>
        <item>(973) 655-7418</item>
        <item>(973) 655-7415</item>
        <item>(973) 655-5144</item>
        <item>(973) 655-7406</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="email">
        <item>benfieldd@mail.montclair.edu</item>
        <item>garrettr@mail.montclair.edu</item>
        <item>herrerach@mail.montclair.edu</item>
        <item>mcdermidk@mail.montclair.edu</item>
        <item>rogersd@mail.montclair.edu</item>
        <item>roholtt@mail.montclair.edu</item>
        <item>clatterbuckm@mail.montclair.edu</item>
        <item>ellerc@mail.montclair.edu</item>
        <item>ibrahimy@mail.montclair.edu</item>
        <item>johnsons@mail.montclair.edu</item>
        <item>koganm@mail.montclair.edu</item>
        <item>vaill@mail.montclair.edu</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="information">
        <item>David Benfield (Professor of Philosophy) received his Ph.D. from Brown University.
            He has published articles in Kant Studien, Philosophy and Phenomenological Research,
            and Philosophical Studies. His research interests include the Wason Task (and why the
            "right" answer isn\u0027t really right),the analysis of fictional objects, the ethical
            and social aspects of cyberspace, and the new public atheism. Courses he regularly
            teaches include: Introduction to Philosophy, Logic, Theory of Knowledge, Philosophy
            of Religion, and Philosophy of Mind.In addition, he is a regular instructor in two
            team-taught courses: GenEd 2002 Contemporary Issues, and the Cooperative Education
            Seminar in the Liberal Arts. He a member of the Executive Committee of the New Jersey
            Regional Philosophical Association.</item>
        <item>Roland Garrett (Professor of Philosophy) received his Ph.D. from Columbia University.
            He has published numerous articles on a variety of philosophical topics. His research
            interests include pragmatism, the philosophy of John Dewey, and the philosophy of art.
            Courses he regularly teaches include: American Philosophy, Metaphysics, and Modern
            Philosophy.</item>
        <item>Chris Herrera (Associate Professor of Philosophy) received his Ph.D. from the
            University of Oklahoma. His research interests include research ethics, the philosophy
            of sport, and the philosophy of science. Courses he regularly teaches include: Theoretical
            and Applied Ethics, Logic, Philosophical Issues in Biomedical Research, and Ancient
            Philosophy.</item>
        <item>Kirk McDermid (Assistant Professor of Philosophy) received his Ph.D. from the
            University of Western Ontario. He has published articles on the philosophy of quantum
            mechanics. His research interests include the philosophy of science, logic, and
            philosophical issues involved in the creationism/evolutionism debate. Courses he
            regularly teaches include: Philosophy of Science, Introduction to Philosophy, and the
            Philosophy of Biology.</item>
        <item>Dorothy Rogers (Associate Professor of Philosophy) earned her Ph.D. as well as a
            master\u0027s in theological studies from Boston University. She is the author of America\u0027s
            First Women Philosophers: Transplanting Hegel, and has served as editor of collections
            of the works of neglected women philosophers, including Catharine Beecher, the women of
            the St. Louis Philosophical Movement, and women in the American academy (1880-1900). She
            served as the coordinating editor for entries on women for theDictionary of Modern
            American Philosophers and is currently serving the same role for the upcoming Dictionary
            of Early American Philosophers, both published by Thoemmes Press. She is a member of the
            Society of Women in Philosophy, the Society for the Study of Women Philosophers, and
            the Society for the Advancement of American Philosophy. She is currently exploring the
            connections between feminism, altruism, and pacifism in political life. Dorothy
            regularly teaches Introduction to Ethics, Social and Political Philosophy, Philosophy
            of Law, and Feminist Legal Theory.</item>
        <item>Tiger Roholt (Associate Professor of Philosophy) received his Ph.D. from Columbia
            University in 2007. His research interests include the philosophy of art, the philosophy
            of music, and phenomenology. Courses he teaches include Philosophies of Art,
            Contemporary Continental Philosophy, Existentialism, and Introduction to Philosophy.
            He is author of Groove: A Phenomenology of Rhythmic Nuance (Bloomsbury Academic, 2014);
            Key Terms in Philosophy of Art (Bloomsbury Academic, 2013); \u0022In Praise of Ambiguity:
            Musical Subtlety and Merleau\u002DPonty\u0022 (Contemporary Aesthetics 11, 2013); \u0022
            Continental Philosophy and Music\u0022 (in The Routledge Companion to Philosophy and
            Music, 2011); \u0022Musical Musical Nuance,\u0022 (Journal of Aesthetics and Art
            Criticism 68, 2010);\u0022Musical Experience\u0022 (in The Oxford Companion to
            Consciousness, 2009\u002Dalso at Oxford Reference Online). He is currently writing
            the chapter, \u0022Phenomenology,\u0022 for The Oxford Handbook of Western Music and
            Philosophy.</item>
        <item>Mark Clatterbuck (Assistant Professor of Religion) received his Ph.D. from The
            Catholic University of America. His area of specialization is the Native American
            encounter with Christianity in the United States. He has published in such scholarly
            journals as Horizons, The US Catholic Historian, Latin American Indian Literatures
            Journal, and Missiology. His most recent projects have been oral religious histories
            focusing on recent developments in Native Catholicism and Native Pentecostalism
            among eastern Montana\u0027s American Indian communities. His book Demons, Saints,
            \u0026 Patriots: Catholic Visions of Native America (1902-1962)was published in
            2009 by Marquette University Press. He teaches Introduction to Religion and courses
            in Native American Religions.</item>
        <item>Cynthia Eller (Professor of Religion) received her Ph.D. from the University of
            Southern California. She has published books on the feminist spirituality movement
            (Living in the Lap of the Goddess, 1995), feminist theory (Am I a Woman? 2004),
            matriarchal myth (The Myth of Matriarchal Prehistory, 2001; Gentlemen and Amazons,
            2011), and pacifism in WWII (Conscientious Objectors and the Second World War, 1991).
            She has written two introductory religious studies textbooks with cloud-based delivery,
            titled Revealing World Religions and Revealing Religion (published by Thinking Strings,
            2004 and 2014). Both are used throughout the United States and Canada. She regularly
            teaches Religions of the World, Introduction to Religion, Atheism, Wicca and
            Neo-Paganism, New Religious Movements, and additional courses for the Women\u0027s
            and Gender Studies program. </item>
        <item>Yasir Ibrahim (Associate Professor of Religion) received his Ph.D. from Princeton
            University. He is a specialist on Islam. Courses he regularly teaches include: Islamic
            Religious Traditions; Jihad: Just War, Holy War; Islamic Ethics and Law; and
            Introduction to Religion. His research interests include twentieth-centuryIslamic
            reform movements in the Middle East, Islamic legal theory and Qur\u0027anic studies.
            His recent publications include articles published in the journals Studia Islamica,
            Journal of Islamic Studies and the Journal of Ecumenical Studies.</item>
        <item>Stephen M. Johnson (Professor of Religion) received his Ph.D. from Yale University.
            Since joining this department in 1971, he has served as President of the American
            Academy of Religion\u0027s Mid\u002DAtlantic Region, and as regional editorial
            representative for the Academy\u0027s Spotlight on Teaching. His own articles and
            review articles have appeared in such scholarly journals as Popular Culture Review,
            Higher Education Exchange, Public Affairs Quarterly, and Implicit Religion. Some
            recent articles include \u0022American Civic Religion after 9/11\u0022 and \u0022Faith,
            Facts, and Fidelity: H. Richard Niebuhr\u0027s Anonymous God.\u0022 He also wrote
            \u0022Mourning in America,\u0022 the concluding chapter of Praeger\u0027s three-volume
            Religion, Death and Dying in America. Dr. Johnson regularly teaches Religion and
            Culture; Religion in North America; Religion and Social Change; Religion and
            Psychology; and Myth, Meaning, and Self.</item>
        <item>Michael S. Kogan (Professor of Religion) received his Ph.D. from Syracuse University.
            He is an active participant in the Jewish-Christian dialogue and the author of several
            very influential articles on its theological foundations. His new book, Opening the
            Covenant: A Jewish Theology of Christianity, was published in November 2007 by Oxford
            University Press. Dr. Kogan\u0027s research interests include contemporary Jewish and
            Christian thought, biblical hermeneutics, and existential theology. Courses he
            regularly teaches include: Old and New Testaments, Contemporary Jewish Thought,
            Religious Existentialism, The Thought of S\u00F8ren Kierkegaard, Heidegger\u0027s Being and
            Time, Modern Theology, and Religion and the Poetic Imagination (T. S. Eliot).</item>
        <item>Lise Vail (tenured Assistant Professor of Religion) received her M.A. from Princeton
            University and Ph.D. from the University of Pennsylvania. She is a Hinduism specialist
            who has lived and worked in southwest India, and has published in the areas of Kashmiri
            Shaiva \u0026 Virashaiva philosophies, and the impact of monks and poet\u002Dsaints on
            the religious communities they serve. She has collaborated on the
            translation/commentary of a 10th\u002Dcentury Kashmiri Sanskrit scripture,
            Recognition of Divine Splendor, and published articles such as \u0022Ascetic
            Masquerade in the Samnyasa Upanisads,\u0022 \u0022Unlike a Fool He Is Not Defiled:
            Purity \u0026 Ethics in the Samnyasa Upanishads,\u0022 and \u0022Guru\u002DCurses\u0026
            Moral Accountability: Popular Ethical Values in N. Karnataka,\u0022 as well as a
            chapter in Gods of Flesh, Gods of Stone: The Embodiment of Divinity in India
            (Columbia University Press), and numerous articles on the saints \u0026 philosophies
            of India for Darshan magazine. Dr. Vail is currently completing a project on Virashaiva
            lineage gurus (15th-20th centuries) and another on monks in late 19th\u002Dcentury
            Anglo-Indian court cases. She teaches broadly in Asian and World Religions, including
            courses entitled Hinduism, Buddhism, Taoism, Mysticism, Yoga Texts, and Death, Dying
            \u0026 Afterlife.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="graduate_names">
        <item>Rika Dunlap</item>
        <item>Peter LaGreca</item>
        <item>Natalie Rusciani</item>
        <item>Sean Skedzielewski</item>
        <item>James Owen</item>
        <item>Ron Chicken</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="graduate_information">
        <item>I am currently a Ph.D. candidate for philosophy at the University of Hawaii, Manoa.
            My experiences at Montclair State University solidified my career path to study
            comparative philosophy, a discipline that compares and contrasts philosophical ideas
            rooted in different cultures. During my undergraduate education (Class of \u002707), I
            majored in philosophy with a minor in legal studies because I was fascinated with the
            power of reasoning that epitomizes much of philosophy and jurisprudence. Immersed in
            the study of classical and modern philosophy, I came to realize that even within
            Western philosophy there are distinct sets of ideas rooted in subtle cultural
            differences. Fascinated with this knowledge, I became interested in non-Western
            philosophy, particularly Asian philosophy, to make sense of the ideas inherent in
            my own culture. Legal studies complemented my study of philosophy, for law embodies
            the ideas deeply entrenched in the cultural paradigm within the United States.\n \n As
            an international student from Japan, I was active within the international community
            at the university. I worked as a student assistant at the Office of International
            Services, and I also became a student representative for International Student
            Organization. I worked closely with other international students and learned the
            importance of cross \u002D cultural dialogues to improve the overall wellbeing of the
            student community. This lesson is something that I still treasure and apply in my
            study of comparative philosophy. I believe that cross-cultural studies not only
            enhance the breadth of philosophical discourses, but also deepen our analyses,
            allowing us to critically reflect on our own mindsets. My experiences at Montclair
            State University enriched my life enormously and gave the foundation upon which
            I develop my work in comparative philosophy now.</item>
        <item>Peter C. LaGreca, Esq., was awarded a Bachelor of Arts, Summa Cum Laude, from
            Montclair State University, where he held a dual major in Jurisprudence and
            Philosophy. Mr. LaGreca earned a Juris Doctor from Pace University School of Law,
            where he was a Senior Associate on the Pace International Law Review
            (ranked in the top 33\u0025 of all international specialty law reviews and journals
            worldwide). Mr. LaGreca is the author of “Natural Rights in a Positive World:
            Do Habeas Rights Extend to Non\u002DCitizens Detained Abroad?” (Inderscience Publishers),
            an international authority on habeas corpus.\n \n Mr. LaGreca received the honor of Pace
            Law School\u0027s Pro Bono Justice Service Award for Extraordinary Service as a result of
            his work with the Morris County Prosecutor\u0027s Office and the Law School\u0027s Foreclosure
            \u0026 Predatory Lending Defense Clinic. While serving with the Prosecutor\u0027s Office, Mr.
            LaGreca assisted in the investigation and prosecution of cases within the Trial Team,
            Major Crimes Unit, Sex Crimes Unit, Domestic Violence Unit, Juvenile Unit, Appellate
            Unit, Fraud Unit, and Narcotics Unit/Intelligence Crime Task Force. Among his many
            responsibilities, Mr. LaGreca handled all facets of motion practice in the Superior
            Court and proposed recommendations to senior staff on office policy and law
            enforcement procedure. Prior to this position, Mr. LaGreca proudly served the
            United States District Court in the Chambers of the Hon. Esther Salas, United
            States District Judge for the District of New Jersey, and the Hon. Tonianne J.
            Bongiovanni, Magistrate Judge for the same District.</item>
        <item>I graduated in 2010 with a BA in Philosophy and English, with a minor in Religion.
            I currently work full\u002D time as a copy editor for an advertising agency. While making
            language better may seem like a strictly literary pursuit, the art of communicating
            knowledge dips just as deeply into my Philosophy degree, particularly epistemology.
            What does the audience need to know\u003F What type of knowledge is it\u003F How does this
            medium communicate that\u003F Is it the best medium to use\u002Dhow or why\u003F \n \n
            When I\u0027m not copy editing, I\u0027m blogging about feminism, particularly body
            acceptance. The Philosophy and Religion Department has given me lots of
            resources\u002D whether they be traditions of thought, rhetorical techniques, or
            recognition of logical fallacies\u002Dto advocate for the things I believe in.
            I\u0027m also working on a novel that explores the unique ethical and existential
            struggles facing a fictional God of Chaos; the so\u002D far 55,000\u002D word
            endeavor would not have been possible without the amazing things I learned in the
            fourth floor of Dickson.</item>
        <item>I graduated from MSU in August of 2012 with a B.A. in philosophy, and in May of 2014
            I completed my M.A. in philosophy from Duquesne University. I\u0027ve presented my work at
            a number of conferences, and am currently focused on getting some of my work published.
            I am considering pursuing a Ph.D. in the near future or possibly taking the skills I\u0027ve
            acquired and applying them in the private sector. Presently I am teaching philosophy
            courses at Rowan University. My time at Montclair prepared me very well for graduate
            level work, and the transition was a very easy one for me.</item>
        <item>James Owen studied Music Education and Minored in Philosophy at Montclair. While
            at Montclair James became interested in philosophy by reading primary texts and writing
            a personal \u0022philosophy of education\u0022 in a philosophy of education class.
            James found the possibility of contributing to a field by research and careful
            reflection to be refreshing and interesting. After completing a Minor in philosophy
            and further developing his ability to deal with primary texts, James started a reading
            group on Martin Heidegger and Maurice Merleau\u002DPonty, which lasted for three years.
            During the end of his undergraduate studies and during his two years working as a music
            teacher in a public school, James began synthesizing the skills from studying
            philosophy with music education and participating and presenting at conferences.
            James is currently attending KU Leuven in Leuven Belgium for an MA in Philosophy
            and planning on continued graduate study of Philosophy of Education.</item>
        <item>With seven family members and four generations of successful alums, choosing to
            attend Montclair State University was both one of the easiest and best decisions I
            have ever made. I graduated in \u002709 after majoring in Classics and Religious
            Studies, as well as earning a minor in Philosophy. In addition to my classroom
            education, I left Montclair with lifelong friends, irreplaceable memories and an
            unforgettable student experience. I participated in intramural sports and was involved
            with countless organizations. I was also elected and served two terms as Student
            Government President.\n \n
            After graduation I pursued a Master\u0027s degree at Princeton Theological Seminary
            in Theology and Philosophy. Building upon the foundation I received from Montclair
            State, I made it a priority to excel both inside and outside the classroom at
            Princeton. Academically I pushed myself beyond the normal requirements with PhD
            seminars at Princeton University. I studied abroad in India and received a fellowship
            to study in Berlin, Germany. As a full time student I also held leadership roles in
            intramural sports and took on a unique internship working twenty hours a week at the
            State Psychiatric Hospital in Trenton, NJ while again serving as a Student Government
            President. I credit both my academic and extracurricular success at Princeton with the
            education and mentoring I received from Montclair State University and its superb
            faculty and administrators.\n \n
            Since graduating from Princeton I have been working as a pastor in Gloucester City,
            NJ. Over the past two years I helped restart a youth program at the Highland Park
            Church of God, worked in the local schools as a substitute teacher, and was elected
            to the city\u0027s local minister\u0027s ecumenical association as Secretary Treasurer.
            Following my wedding in June 2014, I plan to continue my education and pursue a
            Juris Doctorate at the University of Georgia. I am grateful to the professors in both
            the Philosophy \u0026 Religion and Classics Departments at Montclair, who have always
            encouraged and supported me, both as a student and as an alumnus. I wish the best of
            luck to all graduating Red Hawks and urge them to make Montclair proud as they follow
            their dreams and help create tomorrow.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_religion_minor">Religion Minor</string>
    <string name="title_activity_religion_major">Religion Major</string>


</resources>
